Andrew Green

 $Web\ Developer\ |\ Charlotte,\ NC,\ 28208\ |\ Email:\ \underline{andrewgreer2015@gmail.com}\ |\ Phone:\ (828)773-8001$

Portfolio: https://andrewpaulgreer.github.io/andrew-portfolio/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewpgreer/Github: https://github.com/andrewpaulgreer |

Summary:

I am currently a front-end developer and graduate of the UNCC coding bootcamp. I specialize in the MERN stack for web development, including kills in both the front end and back end. I would love to work with several current, and up to date technologies with relation to front-end, full stack, and mobile development.

Skills:

Front-end: HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, jQuery, Ajax, RESTful API creation/consumption, handlebars.js, Bootstrap, Bulma, Twilio, Twilio Flex, TwiML, Jest.

Backend: Node.js, GraphQL, MySQL, Mongodb, MySQL Server, express, sequelize ORM, Mongoose ORM, passport.js, Firebase.

Projects:

Easyfish Local

Apple: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1529454342#?platform=iphone

Android: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.easyfish.esayfishlocalandroid&hl=en_US Easyfish Local is a mobile application used by service industry workers to post images based on geotracking data to increase search results.

Technology used:

• React Native, Redux, React Navigation, CSS3, Google Firebase, Expo, firebase auth, RESTful API Creation, Expo CLI.

Let's Guess | https://github.com/lynseahoss/Lets-Guess | https://andrewpaulgreer.github.io/andrew-portfolio/

Let's Guess is an online browser-based rendition of the classic "Guess Who?" game. This is a simple, and easy to play game utilizing several current technologies such as React, JS, and MongoDB to power the functionality, logic, and storage.

Technology used:

• React, Bulma, HTML5, Javascript, react router, react context, MongoDB, Mongoose ORM, Node.js, Passport, RESTful API's.

ShopByYou | https://github.com/JRivera-31/ShopByYou | https://shopbyyou.herokuapp.com/

Template based online store to demonstrate knowledge of how an ecommerce platform works. ShopByYou is a full stack application that sends client-side input to a MySQL database and retrieves the information using express.

Technology used:

• Semantic UI, Handlebars, Multer, Google Cloud Bucket, bycrypt.js, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js, Sequelize, MySQL, Express, Express-Handlebars, Passport, Express-Session.

Professional Experience:

Easyfish Marketing, Charlotte, NC

April 2020 - Present

Frontend Developer

- Acted as the sole Programmer for a React Native mobile application for both android and iOS, linking service workers with their company's google footprint via geo tracking of the metadata on images taken at job sites.
- Experienced with deploying mobile applications to both Apple App store, and Google Play Store.
- Mobile application will increase location matched search results on the basis of the geographic location of before/ after photos uploaded to a firebase DB supported by google and create communication with Google My Business via API calls to firebase.
- Worked with Google's Play Store Console, Android SDK's, during deployment.
- Tested mobile application using different screen sizes, and OS versions to assure best practices, UI, responsiveness, and accessibility remained consistent.
- Use of RESTful API's to connect Google Firebase to mobile application.
- Building a contact center application configuring Twilio flex with our ActiveCampaign CRM to create an in-house call management platform that will allow salespeople / client service workers to manage inbound and outbound calls more efficiently.
- Exposure to programming an AI web chat bot through Twilio services, as an add-on to client websites to handle commonly asked questions, in order to reduce customer care costs.
- Participating in daily standup meetings to discuss what we shall be developing for the day.
- Given flexibility and decision-making abilities with regards to tools and technologies used in projects.

Technologies Used:

 React.js, React Native, React Plugins, React Reducer and Redux (state management), react hooks, functional components, class-based components, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, Axios, MVC, CRUD, HTML, CSS, REST API creation / consumption, TwilML scripting, Twilio API, Twilio Flex, Firebase cloud.

Ettain Group, Charlotte, NC

June

2019- April 2020

Technical Recruiter

- Built a network of 100+ professionals with varying skill sets in the technology field who were presented to ettain group's reputable clients in the financial services industry.
- Creatively identify, build relationships with, recruit and place top professionals in positions with Fortune 50 clients.
- Utilize interpersonal skills to create and manage relationships with both the professionals, and clients.
- Exposure to technical interviewing processes for different IT skill sets, which included: Scrum Masters, Agile Coaches, Project Managers, Developers, QA's, BA's, and many more.

Easyfish Marketing, Hickory, NC

July

2017-June 2019

Digital Marketing Specialist

- Worked with WordPress Engine to update client websites.
- Improved client's digital marketing campaign quality score from a 3.1 to a 9.8 using Google quality score scale.

- Lowered the average client digital marketing cost by 20 percent by improving quality scores.
- Crafted effective and stunning advertisements through Google Search, Google Display, Facebook, and Instagram.
- Communicated with clients and team members through use of project management software.

Leadership:

President of the Eta Beta Chapter of Sigma Nu Fraternity East Carolina University

Feb

2016-Dec. 2016

- Utilized communication and leadership skills to expand an organization from 17 members to 85 members.
- Managed an organization of 85 members, leading them towards the common goal of gaining the approval of a petition, receiving several community service awards in the process.

Education:

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC

April

2020 - July 2020

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

East Carolina University College of Business, Greenville, NC

Graduated: May 2019

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Marketing

Major GPA: 3.750 Graduated Cum Laude